Xiao Ling Ph.D. Candidate in Systems modeling Virginia Commonwealth University

Summary

Highly experienced in mathematical modeling, data processing, and statistical interpretation and prediction. I would welcome the opportunity in a data/analytical science position to apply mathematical, statistical, and programming skills to conceptualize, build, and implement intelligent systems.

SKILLS

- Communication: Presented both in business and academia. Toastmaster member since 2015.
- Problem-solving: Developed Executive Dashboard, simplifying reporting and data consolidation procedures.
- Technology: R, Scala, Apache Spark, SQL, SAS, VBA, C
- Science: Decision Analytics, Statistics, Optimization, Mathematical Modeling, Signal Processing, Pattern Recognition
- Soft Skills: Attention to detail, Strong sense of commitment, High in grit.

EXPERIENCE

Virginia Commonwealth University

Virginia, USA

Graduate Teaching Assistant

July 2017 - Present

Website: maovurin.github.io

Email: lingx@vcu.edu

Phone: (347)-841-6580

- $\circ~$ Collaborates with faculty to develop machine learning algorithms.
- $\circ~$ Delivered research presentations at well recognized conferences.
- o Lectured, instructed labs, proctored exams, graded tests and assignment for general courses in mathematics.

The University of Toledo

Ohio, USA

Teaching Assistant

Jan 2016 - Jun 2017

o Lectured, instructed labs, proctored exams, graded tests and assignment for general courses in mathematics.

General Electric Healthcare

Shanghai, China

Demand Planning Analyst

Sep 2012 - Feb 2016

- Implemented demand planning with configuration of production requirements, planning book, forecasting strategies (Time series analysis and linear regression).
- o Developed multiple ad-hoc Visual Basic for applications in forecasting ,data cleaning, data visualization.
- Configured APO Data Mart with Key Figures, Characteristics, Data Sources, and Info Cubes to store historical sales invoice data which is gathered from R/3 and non-R/3 systems.
- Maintained global executive supply & demand planning report.
- Training team members on various techniques.

EDUCATION

Virginia Commonwealth University

Virginia, USA

Doctor of Philosophy in Systems Modeling and Analysis

Aug 2017 - Exp. Summer 2021

The University of Toledo

Ohio, USA

Master of Science in Statistics

Aug 2015 - Jun 2017

Saginaw Valley State University

Saginaw, USA Aug 2009 - Jun 2011

 $The\ Master\ of\ Business\ Administration$

0

University of Shanghai for Science and Technology

Shanghai, China

Bachelor of Power Plant and Thermal engineering

Aug 1998 - Jun 2003

Research Areas

- Theory/algorithms for L_1 -norm subspace estimation.
- Subspace learning Applications to computer vision.
- Algorithms implementation on the parallel processing framework Apache Spark in cloud AWS, Azure and GCP.

Ongoing Project

• **Kernel** L_1 -**PCA** Developing a kernel version of L_1 -norm PCA

PUBLICATIONS

- Xiao Ling, Paul Brooks, L_1 -norm regularized L_1 -norm best-fit line problem The 15th INFORMS Virtual Workshop on Data Mining and Decision Analytics
- Xiao Ling, Paul Brooks, Image Denoising via patch based L_1 -norm principal component Analysis SPIE Defense + Commercial Sensing

Research Accomplishments

- Apache Spark(Scala) Package: L_1 -norm regularized L_1 -norm best-fit line algorithm.
- R Package: Image Denoising via patch based L₁-norm principal component analysis.
- C: Kernel L_1 -principal component analysis.

Additional experience

- Project Coordinator with Shanghai China electric green technology group (Sep 2003 Aug 2004).
- Sales Consultant with several companies (Sep 2004 Jul 2006).
- Instrument Technician with Shanghai New Shanghua Polymer Material Company Limited (Jul 2006 Jul 2009).
- Finance Analyst with Craft Company Inc.(Jul 2010 Apr 2011).
- Sales Administrator with Dahlia Fashion (Sep 2011 Feb 2012).
- Outside Sales with Monda Window and Door Systems, Inc. (Mar 2012 Jun 2012).

Professional Societies

- Institute for Operations Research and Management Science (INFORMS) Quality, Statistics & Reliability Section and Optimization Society Subdivision
- The international society for optics and photonics(SPIE)